Finding Aid for Affirmative Action Office (University of Michigan) records 1969-1993
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Commission for Women
  - Administrative Files
    - General Correspondence
      - 1976 (Box 6)
      - 1977-1980 (Box 6)
    - Goals and Priorities of the Commission, 1976 (Box 6)
    - Grievance/Complaints
      - Grievance Procedure, 1971-1974 (Box 6)
      - ISR Grievance Procedure, 1971-1972 (Box 6)
      - Pre-Grievance Counseling, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
      - Third Step Grievances, 1974 (Box 6)
    - HEW, 1970-1974; 1979 (Box 6)
    - Honorary Degrees, 1973 (Box 6)
    - Joint Michigan Council of Women in Higher Education, 1972-1973 (Box 6)
    - Management Advisory Group, 1973 (Box 6)
    - Michigan Women in Administration, 1973 (Box 6)
    - Minutes of CFW, 1971-1979 (scattered dates) (Box 6)
    - Nepotism, 1971-1973 (Box 6)
    - News Releases, 1971-1973; 1976-1977 (Box 6)
    - Nordin, Virginia D., 1971-1973 (Box 6)
    - On the Majority Side (weekly column in Michigan Daily), 1977 (Box 6)
    - Performance Evaluation Procedure (Clerical), 1974 (Box 6)
    - Personnel
      - Clerical Concerns, 1971-1975 (Box 6)
      - Part-Time Employment, 1971 (Box 6)
      - Policies, 1971-1972 (Box 6)
      - Professional/Administrative Study, 1972-1973 (Box 6)
      - Survey of Non-Academic Employees, 1962; 1964 (Box 6)
    - Phi Delta Kappa, 1971-1973 (Box 6)
    - PROBE into the Status of Women at the University of Michigan, 1970-1972 (Box 6)
    - Professional and Administrative Salary Study, 1972 (Box 6)
    - Program for Returning Women Students (UM-Flint), 1973 (Box 6)
    - Promotional Opportunities Program, 1972-1974 (Box 6)
    - Regents, 1972-1973; 1977-1978 (Box 6)
    - Reports
      - CFW Activities, 1971-1980 (Box 6)
      - Discrimination and Women Workers (Malcolm S. Cohen), 1970 (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous, 1971-1978 (Box 6)
      - Office Subcommittee, 1981 (Box 6)
      - Sex-Related Income Differentials Among Academic Employees at the University of Michigan (Mary Fox), 1971-1973 (Box 7)
    - Retirement Benefits, 1971-1979 (Box 7)
    - Retreat, 1972; 1979 (Box 7)
    - Salary Compression, 1973 (Box 7)
    - Schools and Departments
      - Art, 1973 (Box 7)
      - Business Administration/Alpha Kappa Psi, 1973-1976 (Box 7)
      - Engineering, 1970-1973; 1975-1976 (Box 7)
      - English, 1972-1973 (Box 7)
      - Geology and Mineralogy, 1972-1973 (Box 7)
      - Law School, 1971-1975 (Box 7)
      - LSA, 1971-1974 (Box 7)
      - Mathematics, 1972 (Box 7)
      - Michigan Union, 1975 (Box 7)
      - Miscellaneous, 1971-1974 (Box 7)
      - Natural Resources, 1973 (Box 7)
      - Pharmacy, 1971 (Box 7)
      - Public Health, 1973 (Box 7)
      - Rackham Graduate School, 1971-1976 (Box 7)
      - University Hospital Pharmacy, 1971 (Box 7)
      - University Library, 1971-1972 (Box 7)
    - Seminars
      - Affirmative Action Seminar with Plant Department, 1974 (Box 7)
      - U of M Women, 1973
        - General File (Box 7)
        - Speeches (Box 7)
        - Flint and Dearborn Campuses (Box 7)
    - Sex Discrimination, 1971-1973 (Box 7)
    - Sick Time, 1973-1975 (Box 7)
    - Standard Practice Guide, 1971-1973 (Box 7)
    - Summer Orientation Program, 1973-1975 (Box 7)
    - Tenure (Part-Time), 1969-1974 (Box 7)
    - Training Programs, 1972-1973 (Box 7)
    - Tri-Commission (UM, MSU, WSU), 1974-1976 (Box 7)
    - Turnabout (Script for Slide Show), 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - University of Michigan Employees' Credit Union, 1972 (Box 7)
    - University Wide Goals and Timetables, 1969-1972 (Box 7)
    - Women and Credit, 1973 (Box 7)
    - Women's Advocate, 1970-1974 (Box 7)
    - Women's Forum, 1973 (Box 7)
    - Women's Information Fair, 1971; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Women's Information Network
      - Bulletin, 1972-1982 (Box 7)
      - General File, 1972-1983 (Box 7)
    - Women's Legislative Caucus, 1975 (Box 7)
    - Women's Report (Program on WUOM), 1972-1979 (Box 7)
    - Women's Studies Program, 1972-1977 (Box 7)
    - Wyatt, Addie, Speech (Audio Cassette), April 9, 1976 (Box 7)
    - Cluster Reports, 1971-1972 (Box 25)
    - Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 25)
    - Minutes, 1971-1979; 5 folders (Box 25)
    - Office Subcommittee Report, March 1981 (Box 25)
    - Survey of clerical workers, June 1981 (Box 25)
    - WIN (Women's Information Network) Bulletin, 1972-1985; 2 folders (Box 25)
- Advisory Committee on Affirmative Action Programs
  The Advisory Committee on Affirmative Action Programs was formed in 1977 as an advisory body to the director of the Affirmative Action Office. Subgroup records (.6 linear feet) include material on the history and purpose of the group, as well as meeting agendas and minutes from 1979 to 1985. Topics addressed by the committee and documented in the files include student recruitment and retention, grievance procedures, and administrative appointments.
  - Administrative Files
    - Agenda/Minutes, 1979-1985; 6 folders (Box 25)
    - General, 1979-1986; 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Membership, 1982-1985; 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Membership, Noncurrent, 1977-1983; 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Organization, History and Purpose, 1977-1980 (Box 25)
    - "People and Issues in Equal Opportunity", October 7, 1981 (Box 25)
- Council for Minority Concerns
  A progeny of the 1976 reorganization, the Council for Minority Concerns is a voluntary group of persons from the University community who assist the Affirmative Action Office in an advisory capacity to implement their program on Minority Concerns. The subgroup (.3 linear feet) includes a three-year run of the council's newsletter and a 1983 survey of minority faculty concerns relating to recruitment, promotion, and training, as well as files of general correspondence.
  - Administrative Files
    - CMC Newsletter, 1979-1982 (Box 25)
    - Correspondence, 1979-1982; 4 folders (Box 25)
    - Survey (minority faculty concerns), 1983 (Box 25)